Tony Schwartz Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
- Series 2. Business and Professional Materials, 1940–2005, 54 linear feet
  - Client projects: political campaigns, 1956–1997
    - Correspondence, scripts, and other materials for the Don't Bankrupt Washington campaign, 1981–1982 (Box-folder 68/10)
      Material for the political action committee's campaign for the passage of Washington state Initiative 394.
    - Scripts for John Dow's campaign, undated (Box-folder 68/11)
      Material for John Dow's 1974 reelection campaign for U.S. representative from New York.
    - Scripts, clippings, and client papers for the Michael Dukakis campaign, 1988 (Box-folder 68/12-14)
      Material for Michael Dukakis's 1988 presidential election campaign.
      Includes one script hand written on a paper napkin.
      See also memo about the Dukakis campaign and a subject file about the campaign.
    - Scripts for Clive Duval's campaign, undated (Box-folder 69/1)
      Material for Clive Duval's 1970 campaign for U.S. senator from Virginia, including a voice talent record for radio spots.
      Includes two handwritten scripts.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and client papers for Rufus Edmisten's campaign, 1983 (Box-folder 69/2)
      Material for Rufus Edmisten's 1983-1984 North Carolina gubernatorial campaign, including Survey of Political Attitudes in North Carolina prepared by Joseph Napolitan.
    - Correspondence and client papers for Dave Evans's campaign, 1980 (Box-folder 69/3)
      Material for Dave Evans's 1980 campaign for U.S. representative from Indiana's 6th Congressional District, including a Survey of Voter Attitudes and Opinions prepared by David A. Cooper Associates.
    - Correspondence and scripts for Stanley Fink's campaign, 1980, undated (Box-folder 69/4)
      Material for Stanley Fink's 1980 campaign for New York state Assemblyman.
    - Correspondence, scripts, clippings, client papers, and court documents for David Finnegan's campaign, 1983–1985, undated (Box-folder 69/5)
      Material for David Finnegan's 1983 campaign for mayor of Boston, Massachusetts, including correspondence and legal papers for a civil suit against the Finnegan for Boston Committee by New sounds, Inc.
    - Clippings and client papers for the Tom Foley campaign, 1978, undated (Box-folder 69/6-9)
      Material for Tom Foley's 1978 campaign for U.S. representative from Washington's 5th Congressional District, including a survey of voter attitudes and opinions prepared by David Cooper.
    - Correspondence and client papers for the Tom Foley campaign, 1980, undated, (1 folder) (Box 69-70, Box 69, Box 70)
      Material for Tom Foley's 1980 campaign for U.S. representative from Washington's 5th Congressional District, including a survey of voter attitudes prepared by Dresner, Morris & Tortorello Research.
    - Correspondence, clippings, and client papers for the Tom Foley campaign, 1992, undated (Box-folder 70/2-5)
      Material for Tom Foley's 1992 campaign for U.S. representative from Washington's 5th Congressional District, including a survey of voter attitudes prepared by Mellman & Lazarus, Inc.
    - Color slides of Eastern Washington locations for the Tom Foley campaign, 1992 (Box 203)
      Forty-four 35 mm color slides taken for Tom Foley's 1992 campaign for U.S. representative from Washington's 5th Congressional District in Eastern Washington. The slides are labeled and include images of road construction on Rt. 395; a wheat combine at work in a field; the Clarkston, Washington, senior center; Southway Bridge on the Snake River near Clarkston; Main Street, the Touchet River, and the courthouse in Dayton, Washington; fish ladders at the Little Goose Dam on the Snake River; the Veterans Affairs (VA) hospital and Tom Foley's office in Walla Walla, Washington; and the Port of Wilma on the Snake River.
    - Correspondence for the Sanford Garelik campaign, 1972-10-30–1973-01-17 (Box-folder 71/1)
      Material for Sanford Garelik's 1972 campaign for mayor of New York City.
    - Correspondence, scripts, clippings, and client papers for the John Joseph Garrahy campaign, 1976, undated (Box-folder 71/2-4)
      Material for John Joseph Garrahy's 1976 Rhode Island gubernatorial campaign, including a survey of voter attitudes prepared by Hart Research Associates.
    - Correspondence, scripts, clippings, and client papers for the Jay Goldin campaign, 1981, undated (Box-folder 71/5-6)
      Material for Jay Goldin's 1981 campaign for comptroller of New York City.
    - Lettering for Jay Goldin campaign messages, circa 1981 (Box-folder 225/7)
      White lettering on black paper for use in unspecified promotional material, for Jay Goldin's 1981 campaign for comptroller of New York City (running against John C. Dearie).
    - Correspondence, scripts, clippings, and client papers for the Jay Goldin campaign, 1985, undated (Box-folder 71/7)
      Material for Jay Goldin's 1985 campaign for comptroller of New York City.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and other materials for the Jay Goldin campaign, 1989, undated, (1 folder); (9 folders); (10 folders) (Box 71-73, Box 71, Box 72, Box 73)
      Material for Jay Goldin's 1988 campaign for mayor of New York City.
      See also the subject file on this campaign.
    - Correspondence and scripts for the Mike Gravel campaign, 1970–1974, undated (Box-folder 74/1)
      Material for Mike Gravel's 1974 reelection campaign for U.S. senator from Alaska.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and other materials for the Mark Green campaign, 1980, undated (Box-folder 74/2)
      Material for Mark Green's 1980 campaign for U.S. representative from New York.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and other materials for the Mark Green campaign, 1993, undated (Box-folder 74/3)
      Material for Mark Green's 1993 campaign for New York City public advocate.
    - Contract for the Gene Guess campaign, 1972 (Box-folder 74/4)
      Material consists of an unsigned contract for Tony Schwartz's work on Gene Guess's 1972 campaign for U.S. senator from Alaska.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and client papers for the Vance Hartke campaign, 1970, undated (Box-folder 74/5)
      Material for Vance Hartke's 1970 campaign for U.S. senator from Indiana.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and client papers for the Paula Hawkins campaign, 1980, undated (Box-folder 74/6)
      Material for Paula Hawkins's 1980 campaign for U.S. senator from Florida.
    - Correspondence and client papers for the Paula Hawkins campaign, 1986, undated (Box-folder 74/7)
      Material for Paula Hawkins's 1986 campaign for U.S. senator from Florida.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and clippings for the Luther Hodges campaign, 1977–1978, undated (Box-folder 74/8-9)
      Material for Luther Hodges Jr.'s 1978 primary and runoff campaigns for the Democratic candidacy for U.S. senator from North Carolina
    - Correspondence, scripts, and other materials for the Ted Hughes campaign, 1986, undated (Box-folder 74/10)
      Material for Ted Hughes's 1986 campaign for probate judge of Ingham County, Michigan.
    - Scripts, photographs, and other materials for the Hubert Humphrey campaign, 1968–1977 (Box-folder 74/11)
      Material for Hubert Humphrey's 1968 U.S. presidential campaign. Includes a bank check made out to Tony Schwartz from the Humphrey for President Committee.
      Preservation note: The check is mounted and encapsulated in Mylar.
    - Hubert Humphrey color portrait negative, circa 1968 (Box-folder OSU 1/1)
      One 8x5 inch color negative.
    - Correspondence and other material for the Israel Labour Party campaign, 1987-11–1988-08-01 (Box-folder 74/12)
      Material concerning Tony Schwartz's consulting activity for the Israel Labour Party.
    - Correspondence for the Lyndon Baines Johnson campaign, 1984-06-07 (Box-folder 74/13)
      Letter from the Lyndon Baines Johnson Library indicating that the television spots produced by advertising agency Doyle, Dane and Bernbach for the Lyndon Johnson campaign were donated to that library.
    - Scripts and client papers for the Robert F. Kennedy campaign, 1972, undated (Box-folder 74/14)
      Material for Robert F. Kennedy's 1972 primary campaign for U.S. representative from Massachusetts.
    - Scripts for the Edward M. Kennedy campaign, 1976–undated (Box-folder 74/15)
      Material for Ted Kennedy's 1976 campaign for U.S. senator from Massachusetts.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and other materials for the Edward M. Kennedy campaign, 1979–1980, undated, (2 folders); (6 folders) (Box 74-75, Box 74, Box 75)
      Material for Ted Kennedy's 1980 United States presidential primary campaign.
    - Script and member report for the Frank Keough campaign, 1988-10-31–1988-11-03 (Box-folder 75/7)
      Material for Frank Keough's campaign for Massachusetts State senator.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and client papers for the Robert Killian campaign, 1978, undated (Box-folder 75/8)
      Material for Robert K. Killian's 1978 primary campaign for the Democratic candidacy for governor of Connecticut.
    - Scripts, clippings, photographs, and client papers for the Edward J. King campaign, 1982, undated, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 75-76, Box 75, Box 76)
      Material for Ed King's 1982 Massachusetts gubernatorial reelection campaign.
    - Slides of Ed King, 1982 (Box 203)
      Thirty-one 35 mm color slides taken for Ed King's 1982 campaign for governor of Massachusetts. Images include portrait shots of King with a U.S. flag in the background, as well as images of King at work at his desk, greeting and speaking with an unidentified man, and participating in a meeting.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and client papers for the Ann Klein campaign, 1981, undated (Box-folder 76/4)
      Material for Ann Klein's 1981 New Jersey gubernatorial primary campaign, including a survey of voter attitudes prepared by Peter D. Hart Research Associates.
    - Correspondence and scripts for the Robert Lagomarsino campaign, 1988 (Box-folder 76/5)
      Material for Bob Lagomarsino's 1988 reelection campaign for U.S. representative from California.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and client papers for the Tom Lantos campaign, 1982, undated (Box-folder 76/6-7)
      Material for Tom Lantos's 1982 campaign for U.S. representative from California.
    - Correspondence, scripts, clippings, and client papers for the Blair Lee campaign, 1977–1978, undated (Box-folder 76/8)
      Material for Blair Lee's campaign for governor of Connecticut.
    - Scripts and client papers for the Catherine Lessard campaign, undated (Box-folder 77/1)
      Material for Catherine Lessard's campaign for the Michigan House of Representatives.
    - Scripts and other material for the Liberal Party campaign, 1986, undated (Box-folder 77/2)
    - Correspondence, scripts, and other materials for the Frank Licht campaign, 1970, undated (Box-folder 77/3-6)
      Material for Frank Licht's 1970 Rhode Island gubernatorial reelection campaign.
    - Correspondence, scripts, photographs, clippings, and client papers for the Richard Licht campaign, 1986, undated (Box-folder 77/7)
      Material for Richard Licht's 1986 reelection campaign for lieutenant governor of Rhode Island, including a focus group study prepared by Peter Hart Research Associates.
    - Scripts, photographs, drawings, and client papers for the Jaime Lusinchi campaign, 1982-07-05–1982-07-09, undated (Box-folder 77/8)
      Material for the announcement of Jaime Lusinchi's candidacy for president of Venezuela.
    - Correspondence and client papers for the Paul McCloskey campaign, 1971, undated (Box-folder 77/9)
      Material for Paul "Pete" McCloskey's campaign to secure the Republican Party nomination as presidential candidate in the 1972 general election.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and client papers for the Joseph McGahn campaign, 1981, undated (Box-folder 77/10)
      Material for Joseph McGahn's 1981 campaign for New Jersey State senator.
    - Scripts and client papers for the George McGovern campaign, 1974, undated (Box-folder 77/11-12)
      Material for George McGovern's 1974 reelection campaign for U.S. senator from South Dakota.
    - Correspondence, photographs, clippings, and client papers for the Frank McGuire campaign, 1978–1979, undated (Box-folder 77/13)
      Material for Frank McGuire's campaign for county executive of Erie County, New York.
    - Color slides relating to the Frank McGuire campaign, 1979, Robert L. Smith, photographer (Box 203)
      Five 35 mm color slides showing group portrait images of family members sitting in and standing behind a tree hammock.
    - Campaign plan for the Marvin Mandel campaign, 1970-04-27 (Box-folder 77/14)
      Campaign plan for Marvin Mandel's 1970 Maryland gubernatorial reelection campaign.
    - Correspondence, scripts, clippings, and client papers for the Marjorie Margolies-Mezvinsky campaign, 1992, undated (Box-folder 78/1)
      Material for Marjorie Margolies-Mezvinsky's 1992 campaign for U.S. representative for Pennsylvania's 13th district
    - Correspondence and scripts for the Ruth Messinger campaigns, 1988–1995, undated (Box-folder 78/2)
      Material for various Ruth Messinger campaigns for office in New York City.
    - Correspondence and client papers for Howard Metzenbaum's campaign, 1970s–undated (Box-folder 78/3)
      Material for Howard Metzenbaum's campaign for U.S. senator from Ohio.
    - Survey results from the Bess Meyerson campaign, circa 1980–undated (Box-folder 78/4)
      Material consists of an excerpt from a political survey of a New York City district; probably relates to Bess Meyerson's 1980 campaign for the Democratic Party nomination for U.S. senator from New York.
    - Correspondence, scripts, clippings, and client papers for the Edward Mezvinsky campaign, 1968–1974, undated (Box-folder 78/5)
      Material for Edward Mezvinsky's 1968, 1970, 1972, and 1976 campaigns for U.S. representative from Iowa.
    - Framed Charlie Chaplin photograph with attached Edward Mezvinsky campaign button, between circa 1968 and 1976 (Box 210)
      Photograph signed: "I vote for Tony Schwartz! Edward Mezvinsky, [M.C.?] Iowa."
    - Correspondence, photographs, and other materials for the Edward Mezvinsky campaign, 1979–1980, undated (Box-folder 78/6)
      Material for Edward Mezvinsky's 1980 campaign for U.S. senator from Pennsylvania.
    - Scripts, photographs, clippings, and client papers for the Edward Mezvinsky campaign, 1988, undated (Box-folder 78/7)
      Material for Ed Mezvinsky's 1988 campaign for Pennsylvania Attorney General, including a voting machine ballot.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and clippings for the Walter Mondale campaign, 1984, undated (Box-folder 78/8-9)
      Material for Walter Mondale's 1984 presidential election campaign, including a series of unsolicited memos by Joe Napolitan suggesting strategies for the Mondale campaign.
      See also Joe Napolitan memos concerning the Mondale campaign.
    - Correspondence and client papers for the Brian Moss campaign, 1988, undated (Box-folder 78/10)
      Material for Brian Moss's 1988 campaign for U.S. senator from Utah, including an analysis of opponent Orrin Hatch's voting record.
    - Correspondence, scripts, clippings, and client papers for the Daniel Patrick Moynihan campaign, 1976, undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 78-79, Box 78, Box 79)
      Material for Daniel Patrick Moynihan's 1976 campaign for U.S. senator from New York, including a survey of political attitudes in New York.
    - Correspondence, scripts, clippings, and client papers for the Daniel Patrick Moynihan campaign, 1981–1982, undated (Box-folder 79/3)
      Material for Daniel Patrick Moynihan's 1982 campaign for U.S. senator from New York.
    - Correspondence, scripts, clippings, and client papers for the Daniel Patrick Moynihan campaign, 1988, undated (Box-folder 79/4-5)
      Material for Daniel Patrick Moynihan's 1988 campaign for U.S. senator from New York.
    - Correspondence, scripts, photographs, and client papers for the Tom Murray campaign, 1988, undated (Box-folder 79/6)
      Material for Tom Murray's 1988 campaign for U.S. representative from Ohio.
    - Correspondence, scripts, photographs, clippings, and client papers for the Edmund Muskie campaign, 1972, undated (Box-folder 80/1)
      Material for Edmund Muskie's 1972 campaign for the Democratic Party presidential nomination, including campaign volunteer letters from Tony Schwartz associates.
    - Scripts for the Richard Neal campaign, 1987 (Box-folder 80/2)
      Material for Richard Neal's 1987 campaign for mayor of Springfield, Massachusetts.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and client papers for the Richard Neal campaign, 1990, undated (Box-folder 80/3)
      Material for Richard Neal's 1990 campaign for U.S. representative from Massachusetts.
    - Scripts for the Miriam Nelen campaign, 1981, undated (Box-folder 80/4)
      Material for Miriam Nelen's 1981 campaign for the Springfield, Massachusetts school committee.
    - Scripts and other material for the Gaylord Nelson campaign, 1974, undated (Box-folder 80/5-6)
      Material for Gaylord Nelson's 1974 reelection campaign for U.S. senator from Wisconsin.
    - Correspondence and other materials for the New Jersey Democratic State Committee campaign, 1993, undated (Box-folder 80/7)
    - Correspondence, script, and other materials for the New York Democratic State Committee campaign, 1983, undated (Box-folder 80/8)
      Material for the committee's September 1983 presidential Candidates' Forums.
    - Scripts for the New York State Republican Family Committee campaign, 1991-05 (Box-folder 80/9)
    - Correspondence and scripts for the Philip Noel campaign, 1972-09-08–undated (Box-folder 80/10)
      Material for Philip Noel's 1972 Rhode Island gubernatorial campaign.
    - Scripts, photographs, clippings, and client papers for the Peter O'Connell campaign, 1989, undated (Box-folder 80/11)
      Material for Peter O'Connell's 1989 campaign for mayor of Quincy, Massachusetts.
    - Scripts for the Ralph Ostling campaign, undated (Box-folder 81/1)
      Material for Ralph Ostling's campaign for the Michigan State Legislature.
      M.E.P.A.C. client.
    - Photographs, clippings, and client papers for the Claiborne Pell campaign, 1972, undated (Box-folder 81/2)
      Material for Claiborne Pell's 1972 campaign for U.S. senator from Rhode Island.
    - Correspondence for the Joseph Perrini campaign, 1973-05-04 (Box-folder 81/3)
      Letter from WNBC-TV discussing the form for sponsor identification on ads produced for Joseph Perrini's campaign for Deputy Comptroller of New York City.
    - Scripts and transcripts for the Vince Petiprin campaign, undated (Box-folder 81/4)
      Material for Vince Petiprin's campaign for the Michigan State Legislature.
    - Correspondence, clippings, and client papers for the John Phillips campaign, 1980, undated (Box-folder 81/5)
      Material for John Aristotle Phillips 1980 campaign for U.S. representative from Connecticut.
      See also John Phillips correspondence from 1987 in business correspondence.
    - Scripts and transcripts for the Dean Pridgeon campaign, undated (Box-folder 81/6)
      Material for Dean Pridgeon's campaign for the Michigan State Legislature.
    - Scripts for the Tom Reddin campaign, undated– (Box-folder 81/7)
      Material for Tom Reddin's 1973 primary campaign for the Democratic Party candidacy for mayor of Los Angeles, California.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and other materials for the Harry Reid campaign, 1984, undated (Box-folder 81/8-9)
      Material for Harry Reid's 1984 campaign for U.S. representative from Nevada's 1st District.
    - Correspondence, scripts, clippings, and client papers for the Ogden Reid campaign, 1971–1972, undated (Box-folder 81/10)
      Material for Ogden Reid's 1972 campaign for U.S. representative from New York, including a survey of the political climate in the 24th District.
    - Correspondence and client papers for the Ogden Reid campaign, 1973, undated (Box-folder 81/11-12)
      Material for Ogden Reid's 1974 campaign for U.S. representative from New York, including a survey of political attitudes in the state of New York.
    - Scripts for an Abraham Ribicoff campaign, undated (Box-folder 81/13)
      Material for Abe Ribicoff's 1968 and/or 1974 reelection campaigns for U.S. senator from Connecticut.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and client papers for the Dean Robb campaign, 1986, undated (Box-folder 81/14)
      Material for Dean Robb's 1986 campaign for Michigan Supreme Court, including a report issued by the Citizens' Commission to Improve Michigan Courts entitled How Michigan Citizens View the Courts and Legal System.
    - Correspondence and client papers for the Jay Rockefeller campaign, 1976–1977, undated (Box-folder 82/1-4)
      Material for Jay Rockefeller's 1976 West Virginia gubernatorial campaign.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and other materials for the Robert Roe campaign, 1977, undated (Box-folder 82/5)
      Material for Bob Roe's 1977 primary campaign for the Democratic Party nomination for governor of New Jersey.
      See also the Percy Sutton 1977 New York City mayoral campaign.
    - Correspondence, scripts, clippings, and client papers for the Jim Roosevelt campaign, 1986, undated (Box-folder 82/6)
      Material for Jim Roosevelt's 1986 campaign for U.S. representative from Massachusetts.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and other materials for the Warren Rudman campaign, 1980–1988, undated (Box-folder 82/7)
      Material for Warren Rudman's 1980 campaign for U.S. senator from New Hampshire. Includes a transcription of a 1988 interview with Rudman by CBS news concerning Rudman's experience working with Tony Schwartz.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and client papers for the George Russell campaign, 1971, undated (Box-folder 82/8)
      Material for George Russell's 1971 campaign for mayor of Baltimore, Maryland.
    - Correspondence, scripts, transcripts, and client papers for the Matthew Ryan campaign, 1986, undated (Box-folder 82/9)
      Material for Matthew Ryan's 1986 campaign for Hampden County, Massachusetts, district attorney.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and other materials for the SANE/FREEZE campaign, 1983, undated (Box-folder 82/10)
      Material for the SANE/FREEZE political action committee's anti-nuclear campaign against Wisconsin congressman Les Aspin.
    - Scripts and other materials for the Clyde See campaign, 1984, undated (Box-folder 83/1-2)
      Material for Clyde See's 1984 West Virginia gubernatorial campaign.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and client papers for the Alex Seith campaign, 1978, undated (Box-folder 83/3-6)
      Material for Alex Seith's 1978 campaign for U.S. senator from Illinois.
    - Garry South post-election analysis of the Alex Seith campaign, 1978–1981, undated (Box-folder 84/1)
    - Correspondence, scripts, and other materials for the Alex Seith campaign, 1983–1984, undated (Box-folder 84/2-3)
      Material for Alex Seith's 1984 campaign for U.S. senator from Illinois.
    - Correspondence, scripts, photographs, clippings, and client papers for the Phil Sharp campaign, 1982, undated (Box-folder 84/4)
      Material for Philip Sharp's reelection campaign for U.S. representative from Indiana.
    - Correspondence, scripts, clippings, and client papers for the Bob Short campaign, 1978, undated (Box-folder 84/5)
      Material for Bob Short's campaign for U.S. senator from Minnesota.
    - Correspondence, scripts, and other materials for Isaac Newton Skelton's campaign, 1976, undated (Box-folder 84/6-7)
      Material for Isaac Newton "Ike" Skelton's 1976 campaign for U.S. representative from Missouri.
      See also Ike Skelton correspondence.